Guide to the Leon Kolb collection of Portraits: engravings, etchings, mezzotinits, lithographs, and acquatints, M0871
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 1. Accn 1972-002, 12.0 Linear feet 1647 items (prints)
  - 0477. Frederick Augustus [duke of York and Albany bp. of Osnabruck] prince of Great Britain, 1763-1827 (Flat-box 4, Folder 4)
    His Royal Highness Frederick Duke of York./(Paint)ed by R.Bowyer. Engraved by John Bromley. London Published by R.Bowyer & M.Parkes Pall Mall 1828./Proof.Bust in oblong looking right. Bust in oblong looking right.Mezzotint.51.2 x 35.o cm.Badly trimmed.
  - 0478. Frederik Hendrik van Nassau-Oramje, governor of Holland, 1584-1647 (Flat-box 4, Folder 4)
    Fredericus Henricus./Dei Gratia Auriaci et Sacri Romani Imperij Princeps./Comes de Nassau etc. Anna 1657./Anselmus van Hulle pinxit. Petr.de Jade sculpsit./Accessit Privileg. Caesareum Regum et Ordimum Hollandiae. Bust in oval booking left.Engraving.34.4 x 25.0 cm.No. 5 from unidentified edittion of Hulle, A.van, Celeberrimi ad pacificandum Chrisriani nominis orbem le~ati,Singer No. 9513/26683.
  - 0479. Frederik III, king of Denmark, duke of Sehleswig Holstein, bp. of Verden, abp. of Bremen, 1609-1670 (Flat-box 4, Folder 4)
    Fredericus Haerer./Norwegiae, Del gratia Dux Sleswici,/Holstatiae, Stormasiae et Dithmarsiae,/Comes in Oldenburg et Delmenhorst./Anselmus van Hulle pinxit. Petr. de lode sculpsit. Accessit Privilegium Casareum (sic.) Cum privilegio Regum et Hollandiae Ordinum. Bust in oval looking left, lettered: "Virtutis Gloria Merses."Engraving.34.2 x 25.6 cm.Singer No. 9517/26735.No. 21 from: Hulle, A. van, Pacificatores orbis Christiani.. .Rotterdam, 1697.
  - 0480. Fredrik V, king of Denmark, 1723-1766 (Flat-box 4, Folder 4)
    Fredericus V./D.G.Daniae, Norvegiae, Vandalorum,/Q,thorumque Rex, Dux Slesvici, Holsatiae, Strinariae/et Dithmarsiae, Comes in Oldenborg et Delmenhorst./Unctus d.IV. Sept. 1747. Peint par C.G.Pilo. Grave par J.M.Preisler Graveur du Roy 1748. Bust in oval looking left.Engraving.33.7 x 22.0 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 9520/25773.
  - 0481. Freron, Elie Catherine, 1719-1776 (Flat-box 4, Folder 5)
    E.C.Fréron./Du Mauvais gout censeur inexorable/De l’ignorance ii dedaigne les cris/ Sa plume aux ecrivains, l’a rendu redoutable/Et son coeur cher a ses amis./A Paris chez Esnauts et Rapilly, rue S.Jacques a la Ville de Coutances A.P.D.R. Dessine par Ch.N. Cochin, 1770./Hubert sculp. Left profile in oval. Engraving. 18.5 x .2.4 cm.
  - 0482. Friedland, Albert Wenzel Eusebius, graf Waldstein [Wallenstein], 1583-1643 (Flat-box 4, Folder 5)
    Albert. Dux. Fritland. Com. Wallest. Etc./Pet. de lode scuip. Ant. van Dyck pirtxit. Cum privilegio. Half-portrait in oblong looking left.Engraving.Singer No. 9648/27170.Dutuit No. 46.3e. Mauquoy-H. No. 40.IV.From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 0483. Friedrich II, der Grosse, King of Prussia, 1712-1786 (Flat-box 4, Folder 5)
    Frederick the Great./J.Chapman sculp.t Engraved for the Encyclopedia Londinensis 1825.Left profile in oval. Equestrian facing row of soldiers in oblong below. Stipple-engraving.16.2 x 11.3 cm.
  - 0484. Fridrich II, der Grosse, king of Prussia, 1712-1786 (Flat-box 4, Folder 5)
    Fredericus Rex Prussiae/et/Br./I.F.Wenzel pict. Reg. pinxit. E.Desrochers Sculpsit Parisiis. Bust in oval looking left, surrounded by symbolic composition.Engraving.30.4 x 19.1 cm.Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0485. Friedrich II, der Grosse, king of Prussia, 1712-1768 (Flat-box 4, Folder 5)
    Friedrich II/König in Prussen Marggraf/zu Brandenburg, des Hell R~5m.Reichs/Ertz CHumierer und ChurrfUrst./M.Diehl delin. C.H.MUller scuip. Bust in oblongish frame looking left. Engraving. 28.7 x 16.7 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0486. Friedrich II, der Weise, elector of Pfalz., 1482-1556 (Flat-box 4, Folder 5)
    Frederic le Sage./Dubois del. Litho de C.Motte. Bust in oval looking right. Lithograph.19.1 x 11.9 cm.
  - 0487. Friedrich V, king of Bohemia, 1596-1632 (Flat-box 4, Folder 5)
    Frederick King of Bohemia./Elector Palatine /Obit 1632. London Published by S.Woodburn 1812. Van Dyck pinxit. R.Dunkarton sculpt. Bust in oblong looking right. Mezzotint.16.0 x 11.0 cm.
  - 0488. Friedrich August I, der Starke KunfUrst von Sachsen, 1670-1733 (Flat-box 4, Folder 5)
    Friedrich August/K6nig von Sachsen, Grosherzog von Warschau etc. etc./C.G.Rasp sculps. Dresde. Bust in oval looking right.Engraving.27.8 x 19.0 cm.Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0489. Friedrich, Markgraf von Brandenburg, 1711-1763 (Flat-box 4, Folder 5)
    Fridericus/Margravius Brandeburgicus, Porusslae, Silesiae, Magne/burgi, Cliviae,luliaci, Montium, Sedini, Pomeraniae, Cassubiorum,/Vandalorum, Megapoleos et CrossaeDux Burgravlus Norimbergensis,/Princeps Halberstadii, Mindae, Camlnae, Vandaliae, Suerini,Raceburgi/& Murini, Comes Hohenzollerae, Marcae, Ravensbergl, Suerini, Dynasta,Ravensteinli, Rostochii, Stargardlae, rellqua./Circuli Franconici Supremus Belli Dux Praefectus trium Legionum cohortium./A.Rosslin ping. G.Eichler Sculp. Knee-piece in Baroque oblong looking right.Engraving.21.4 x 17.0 cm.Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0490. Friedrich Wilhelm I, der Grosse, elector of Brandenburg, 1620-1688 (Flat-box 4, Folder 5)
    Fridericus Wilhelmus/Marchio Brandenburgensis, Sacri Romanj Imperij/Eleetor, et Archicameracius, Dux Magdeburgi, Borussiae,/Juliae, Cliviae et Montium nec non Stetini et Pomeraniae/Dux, Princeps Halberstadij. Mindae, et Rugiae, etc./Anselmus van Hulle pinxit. Petr de lode sculpsit./Cum privilegio Caesari Regum et Hollandiae Ordinum Anno1657. Bust looking left in oval lettered: "Monstra mihi Deus viam qua ambulem." Engraving.34.8 x 25.8 cm.Singer No. 9676/27391.No. 11 from an unidentified edition of Hulle,A.van, Celeberrimi ad pacificandu~ Cristiani nomini orbem Legati.
  - 0491. Friedrich Wilhelm II, king of Prussia, 1744-1797 (Flat-box 4, Folder 6)
    Frederic William II King of Prussia./Crowned at Berlin in the year 1786./J.Pass sculp./Published as the Act directs. Left profile in oval.S tipple-engraving.17.3 x 11.8 cm.
  - 0492. Friedrich Wilhelm III, king of Prussia, 1770-1840 (Flat-box 4, Folder 6)
    Friedrich Wilhelm. /Kronprinz von Preussen./J.Kjrchhoff del./G.W.Lehman sculp./Zum besten vaterländischer Schul-Anstalten/herausgegeben von Magazin fUr Kunst, Geographic und Musik. (Hoffman u. Wolff) Berlin K6nigstrasse No. 3. Bust in octangle looking left.Stipple-engraving.26.8 x 20.6 cm.
  - 0493. Fromhold, Johann, 1602-1653 (Flat-box 4, Folder 6)
    Joannes Fromhold Serenissimo ac Potentissimo/Domino Electori Brandenburgico a consilis intimis et/Judicii Cameralis eiusdemque ad Tractatus Pads Universalis cuin pl plenipotentia Legatus. A.van Hulle pinxit. C.Galle sculp. Bust looking right in oval, lettered:"Pax multa diligentibus legem tuam Domine et non vaccillabunt."Ornamental background. Engraving.
  - 0494. Fuller, Isaac, 1606-1672 (Flat-box 4, Folder 6)
    Isaac Fuller./Ipse pinx. T.Chambars sculp. Bust in oval looking right.Engraving.17.0 x 13.2 cm.
  - 0495. Furtteribach [Furtenbach], Joseph, 1591-1667 (Flat-box 4, Folder 6)
    Josephus Furtenbach Anno Aetatis 44 Chri. 1635./M.Remb: Sca: Knee-piece in lettered oval looking right with "Con la Patienza/S'aquista Scienza" in lower part of oval surrounded by symbolic Baroque composition. On bridge of ship in lower center: "Fultnen in hostes". Under pictoral part: "Viro Spectatisso, Technophilo meritisso/Dn, Josepho Furtenbacho, Patrono, et Compatri bene-merito Praesetem/Iconem quo poterat studio elaboratam L.M0. Joh.Jacob Campan/pinxit. Matthal Rembold aeri incidit: Utergs Gratiss: memoriae eo; Ulmae".Engraving.35.0 x 21.2 cm.Trimmed close to plate-mark.Singer No. 10155/30369.
  - 0496. Furstenberg, Franz Egon, count, bp. of Cologne and Strassburg, 1625-1682 (Flat-box 4, Folder 6)
    Franciscus Egon./Comes in Furstenberg Heiligenberg & Werdenberg/Landgravius in Baer et Stulingen et Hoven Dom.nus In Hausen/Vallis Kintzingeren: et Weitra. Metropol. et Cathedral:/Eccliarum Colonien: Argentoraten: et Minden: respe Chori/Episcopus Thesaurarius et Canonicus Ser.morum Principuni Electoris/Colonien: vti et Archiducis Austriae Leopoldi Guilielmu/Episcopi Argentoraten; respe a Consilijs intimis, aulici/ consilij praeses. Dynasta in Rufach et ad tractatus Norinibergenses/pro Executione pads Legatus Plenipotentiarius./Anno 1650. Anselmus van Hulle pinxit. Petrus de lode sculpsit. accessit privilegium Caesareum. Bust looking right in oval lettered: "Onme regnum in se divisum desolabitur." and "Ad utrumque paratus." On plinths: "Pietate" and "Fortitudine".Engraving.Singer No. 9994/30079.No. 119 from Hulle, A.van, Pacificatores orbis Christiani... Rotterdam, 1697.
  - 0497. Gainsborough, Thomas, 1727-1788 (Flat-box 4, Folder 6)
    Thomas Gainsborough./Esq. R.A. From the original Picture painted by himself in the Council room of the Royal Acadeny./Drawn by J.Jackson. Engraved by H.Meyer. Published No\ 7, 1810 by T.Cadell & W.Davies, Strand, London. Unframed bust in oblong looking right.Lithograph.37.8 x 31.0 cm.Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0498. Galba, SergIus Sulpltius, 7th emperor of Rome, 5-69 A.D. (Flat-box 4, Folder 6)
    Galba,/born in a Villa near/Terracina, reigned 7 Months,/5 Days, killed in ye year of Christ 69. Left profile in oval lettered: "Ser. Sulpi Galba. Imp. Caes. Aug. P.M.TR.P."Engraving.18.0 x 10.7 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Illustration "Vol.XIV page 474", from unidentified book.
  - 0499. Galba, Sergius Sulpitius, 7th emperor of Rome, 5-69 A.D. (Flat-box 4, Folder 6)
    Sergius Galba./VII. Serge Galba nestolt de la maison des Cesars, car elle defallolt en Neron, mais de la Noble Famille des Servlens./I1 fut Ulu Emp. agd de 73 ans par la garde Pretorienne du vivant mesme de Neron. o .les soldats.. .le tueret au milieu de Rome.. le 7 mois de son Empire. Plutar. Right profile in oblong, with six lines of biogr. under portrait.Engraving.28.3 x 19.3 cm.Trimmed close to plate-mark.From an unidentified edition of Suetonius T., Histoire des douze Cesars.
  - 0500. Galba, Serglus Sulpitius, 7th emperor of Rome, 5-69 A.D. (Flat-box 4, Folder 6)
    Ser. Galba. Imp. Caesar. Aug. Tr. P. VII. Right profile in lettered circle. Over portralt"Krlessman lehr kriegen, hie is Galba mmd nit Getuilcus". Under portrait "In 73 jar seines alters und in seiner regie/ rung im VII. monat ward er verrettlich erschlagen".Engraving.24.4 x 20.8 cm.Trimmed close to plate-mark.No. 7 from unidentified German version of Suetonius I; Vita XII Caesarum.
  - 0501. Galen, Johannes A., 1604-1653 (Flat-box 4, Folder 7)
    Johannes A.Galen./PP. Ordinun Belgij In Marl Medlter/raneo maria. Bust in oval looking right. Stipple-engraving.12.3 x 6.7 cm.Badly trimmed.
  - 0502. Galle,Theodor, 1571-1633 (Flat-box 4, Folder 7)
    Theodorus Galle/Calcographus Antverpiae./Ant. van Dyck pinxcit Vorsterinan scuip. Cuni privilegio. Half portrait in oblong looking right.Engraving.23.7 x 15.7 cm.Singer No. 10275/30701.Dutuit No. 88.4e.Mauquoy-H. No. 81.VII.From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 0503. Gallienus, Caesar Publius Licinius Egnatius Augustus, 32d emperor of Rome, ?-268. A.D. (Flat-box 4, Folder 7)
    The Emperor Gallienus./P.Dujardin eng./Gebbie & Co. Unframed left profile.Lithograph.26.0 x 26.7 cm.Lower part of leaf missing; torn from book.
  - 0504. Gassend, Pierre, 1592-1655 (Flat-box 4, Folder 7)
    Pierre, Gassendi. /Jac.Lubin Sculp. Bust in oval looking right.Engraving.25.2 x 19.7 cm.Singer No. 10374/30918.
  - 0505. Gassion, Jean, 1609-1647 (Flat-box 4, Folder 7)
    Jean de Cassion/Mareschal de France./Edelinck Sculp. C.P.R. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving.25.1 x 19.3 cm.Singer No. 10379/30930.
  - 0506. Gaure, Philips, count Egmond, duke of, ?-1682 (Flat-box 4, Folder 7)
    Philippus./Comes Egnundae, Gaurae et Sancti/Imperij Princeps etc. Anselnus van Hulle pinxit. Petr. de Jode sculpsit. Cum privilegio Caesaris Regum et Hollandiae Ordinum 1656. Bust in oval looking left.Engraving.34.4 x 25.4 cm.No. 26 of unidentified series. Singer No. 10413/30995.
  - 0507. Gebelin, A.C. de, 18th cent. (Flat-box 4, Folder 7)
    A.Court de Gebelin./Auteur du Monde Primitif/De diverses Academies, Président du Musée de Paris/Censeur Royal & /A.Pujos ad vivum Del. F.Huot Sculp. 1784./A Paris chez M. DeLaunay Graveur du Rol, Rue de Boucherie No. 2. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 21.9 x 15.0 cm.
  - 0508. Geeraerts, Marcus, the Younger, 1561-1635 (Flat-box 4, Folder 7)
    Marc Garrard/fron a print by Hollar/Se ipse pinx.t 1627. Bannemman exc. Bust in oval looking right.Engraving.19.0 x 14.9 cm.
  - 0509. Geest, Comnelis van de, 1577-1647 (Flat-box 4, Folder 7)
    Cornelius van der Geest/Artis Pictoriae Amator Antverpiae./sculp. Paul Pontius./ Ant, van Dyck pinxcit. Cum privilegio. Knee-piece in oblong looking left. Engraving.24.9 x 17.8 cm. Singer No. 10455/31092. Dutuit No. 54.5e. Mauquoy-H. No. 48.VI. From: Icono~aphy of Vandyke.
  - 0510. Geest, Wybrand Simonsz the Elder, 1592-? (Flat-box 4, Folder 7)
    [Wybrand de Gheest.] C.Eisen mv. R,Gaillard sculp. Bust in oval looking right, surrounded by symbolic composition.Engraving.7.0 x 9.9 cm.Plate-mark trimmed off.From: Descamps J.B., La Vie des Peintres Flamands, Allemands et Hollandais, Paris, 1753-1764.
  - 0511. Geiso [Geusau, Geise], Johann von, 1593-1661 (Flat-box 4, Folder 8)
    Johannes Geyso./Illustrissimae Lantgraviae Hasso-/Cassellanae a Consillis Interioribus, eiusdemque Praefectus Generalis Militiae. fAccessit Privilegium Caesareum. Cum privilegio Regum et Hollandiae ordinum. 1651, Anselmus van Hulle pinxit. Petrus de lode sculpsit. Bust looking right in oval lettered: "Cum deo et virtute."Engraving.31.1 x 20.9 cm.Singer No. 10759/32406.No. 95 from: Pacificatores orbis Christiani, Rotterdam, 1697.
  - 0512. Galee [Lorrain] Claude, 1600-1682 (Flat-box 4, Folder 8)
    Claude Lorraine.fDrawn by J.Jackson R.A. from an original in the possession of the Earl of Mulgrave./Engraved by W.Ward A.R.A London Published Sept. 1.1826 by W.B.Cooke 9. Soho Square. Bust in oval looking slightly right.Mezzotint.13.7 x 13.5 cm.
  - 0513. Gent, Bartholdt van, ca 1648 (Flat-box 4, Folder 8)
    Bartholdus a Gent, Dominus in Loenen et/Maynerswyc Prafectus et Curator AggerumBommeliae,fut et cognominis nec non Tilanae Insulae et Jurisdictionis,/In ConcilioGeneralium ex parte Ordinis Equestris, /Provinciae Geldriae deputatus Legatus Extraordina- rius,/et Plenipotentiarius ad Pacem universalen Monasterij, etc./Anselmus evan Hulle Pinxt.Petrus de Jode sculpsit, 1648 accessit Privilegiuni Caesareuin./Cuni privilegio Regum etHollandiae ordinum. Bust in oval looking left.Engraving.30.8 x 19.6 cm.Singer No. 10543/31397.No. 35 from: Hulle, A. van, Celeberrimi ad pacificandum Christiani nonilnis orbem Legati.... Anvers, 1648.
  - 0514. George I, king of Great Britain, 1660-1727 (Flat-box 4, Folder 8)
    King George I./G.Kneller pinxit. J.Houbraken sculps. Anist. 1746. At Kensington Palace mmpensis Knapton Londini. Bust in lettered oval looking slightly left in Baroque composition.36.1 x 21.6 cm.Singer No. 10575/31623.
  - 0515. George I, king of Great Britain, 1660-1727 (Flat-box 4, Folder 8)
    Georgius D.G. Nag. Brit. Fran. et Hiberniae Rex Fidei Defendor./Brun. et Lumen. Dux.S.R.J. Arch. Thesau. et Prin. Elector/Done from Sir Godfrey Kneller's Painting in GuildHall. J.Faber jun. Fecit./Printed for and sold by Theo.Bowles, next the Chapter House inSt.Paulus Church Yard. Half portrait in oblong looking right.Mezzotint.35.9 x 25.3 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.Singer No. 10576/31671.
  - 0516. George II, king of Great Britain, 1683-1760 (Flat-box 4, Folder 8)
    Georgius Secundus D.G. Mag. Britanniae. Franciae et Hiberniae Rex &/Brun. et Lunen. Dux S.R.I. Arch. Thesau el Princeps Elector & Inauguratus XI. die Octo.bris l727./G Kneller S.R. Imp. et Nag. Brit. Baronet Pinx. Ab Origmnali J.Smith Fecit. Sold by I.Smith at ye Lyon & Crown in Russell Street Covent Garden. Bust in oval looking right.Mezzotint.34.6 x 25.0 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. Singer No. 10576/31680.
  - 0517. George I, of Denmark, prince consort [of queen Anne]of England, 1653-1708 (Flat-box 4, Folder 8)
    Georgius/Daniae Princeps./Petrus a Gunst sculpsit. M.Marrebeeck excudit. Bust in oval looking slightly left.Engraving.36.5 x 26.5 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 10573/31583.
  - 0518. George I, of Denmark, prince consort [of queen Anne]of England, 1653-1708 (Flat-box 4, Folder 8)
    His Royal Highness/Prince George of Denmark /N.Parr Sculp. Bust in oval wreath looking left.Engraving.30.0 x 19.7 cm.Trimmed close to plate-mark
  - 0519. George I, of Denmark, prince consort [of queen Anne]of England, 1653-1708 (Flat-box 4, Folder 8)
    George Prince of Dennark./G.Kneller pinxit. J.Houbraken sculpsit. Amst. 1745. At Kensington Palace./Impensis J. & P.Kmapton, Londini. Bust in lettered oval looking right, surrounded by symbolic Baroque decoration.Engraving.'35.7 x 22.3 cm.
  - 0520. Georg Wilhelm, markgrave of Brandenburg, 1678-1726 (Flat-box 4, Folder 8)
    Georgius Wilhelmus./Dei Gratia Dux Brunsvi/censis et Luneburgensis. etc./Anselnus van Hulle pinxit. Petr. de lode sculpsit./Accessit Privilegium. Caesareum Cum privilegio Regum et Hollandiae ordinum. Bust looking right in oval lettered: "Pietate et lustitia".Engraving.35.2 x 25.3 cm.Singer No. 10569/31544.No. 19 from: Hulle A. van, Pacificatores orbis Christiani... .Rotterdain, 1697.
  - 0521. Gerard, Etienne Maurice, Comte de, 1773-1852 (Flat-box 4, Folder 9)
    Le Mal. Cte. Gerard./Deputé de 1’Oise,/183l./Paris chez Challiou, Editeur rue S. Honore. No.140. Lith. de Lemercier Rue du four S.G.N. 55,/A.Maurin. Bust looking right. Lithograph. 28.6 x 22.7 cm.
  - 0522. Gerbier d'Ouvrilly, Baithasar, 1593-1667 (Flat-box 4, Folder 9)
    Balthasar Gerbier/Il a faict merveille en illuminature, et a demeuré long tempre en Italie, ii fut peintre du Dec de/Bocquingan et apres du Roy d Angleterre le quel lui faisoit Chevalier per sa vertu; et apres son/Agent a Brusselles, en l'an 1630 et a Londres maistre de la Ceremonie, 11 est natif d'Anvers/l'an 1592. Ant, van Dyck pinxit. Jean Meissens excudit. Half-portrait in oblong looking left.Engraving.16.7 x 11.8 cm.Singer No. 10632/32008.From: Meyssens J., The true Effigies of the most eminent Painters....that have flourished in Europe... Engraven,[Anvers], 1694.
  - 0523. Gerbier d'Ouvrilly, Balthasar, 1593-1667 (Flat-box 4, Folder 9)
    Sr. Baithazar Gerbi.~r./Vandyck pinx. T.Chambars sculp. Half-portrait in oblong looking right. Engraving.17.0 x 12.9 cm.
  - 0524. Gericke, Otto von, 1602-1686 (Flat-box 4, Folder 9)
    Otto Gericke,/Patricius et Reipubl./Magdeburgensis Consul,/eiusdeniqe ad Universales/ Pads Tractatus Monasterij/et Osnabrugi Legatus./Anselmus van Hulle pinxit et Corn.Galle sculpsit. Cum privilegio Regum et Hollandiae ordinum./1649. Bust facing viewer in oval lettered: "Libertas, leges et pax sunt optima dona".Engraving.30.5 x 19.6 cm.Singer No. 10654/32141.No. 112 from: Pacificatores orbis Christiani, Rotterdam, 1697.
  - 0525. Germanicus Julius Caesar, 15 B.C.-19 A.D. (Flat-box 4, Folder 9)
    C.Caesar Aug.Germanicus. Pon.M.Tr.Pot.IV. Left profile in lettered circle: "Nicht hochers kan ich an meiner natur loben, damn/die onschamhafftigkeijt"; over portrait: "In 28.iar seines alters, mmd mach den er III. iar und X.nionat das Reich bekummert hett, ward er hemlich ermordt" in lower center.Engraving.23.9 x 20.7 cm.Trimmed close to plate-mark.No.4 from unidentified German version of Suetonius T., Vita XII Caesaruin.
  - 0526. Gevaerts, Jasper, 1593-1666 (Flat-box 4, Folder 9)
    Clarissinius Vir, Casperius Gevartius luris consultus /Archigrammateus Antverpianus, Consiliarius et Histo-/riographug Caesareus./Ant. van Dyck pinxit. Paul du Pont scuip. Cum privilegio. Half-portrait in oblong looking left.Engraving.24.4 x 16.7 cm. Singer No. 10746/32381. Dutujt No. 55,8e. Mauquoy-H. No. 49.X. Trimmed close to plate-mark. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 0527. Gianuzzi, Giulio Romano Pippi de, 1492-1546 (Flat-box 4, Folder 9)
    Jules Romain. Bust in oval baroque frame.Engraving.11.3 x 8.6 cm.Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0528. Gibbons, Grinling, 1648-1720 (Flat-box 4, Folder 9)
    Mr. Grinlin Gibbons./G.Kneller pinx./I.Smith fc. & cxc. Knee-piece with sculpture and compass in oblong looking right. Mezzotint. 32.2 x 26.0 cm. Singer No. 10783/32472.
  - 0529. Gibbons, Grinling, 1648-1720 (Flat-box 4, Folder 9)
    Grinling, Gibbons./G.Kneller pinx. T.Chambars fc. Half-portrait with sculpture head and compass in oblong looking left. Engraving. 16.8 x 13.3 cm.
  - 0530. Gibbs, James, 1682-1754 (Flat-box 4, Folder 9)
    Bust in oval facing viewer. Engraving. 22.3 x 16.2 cm.
  - 0531. Gibson, Edmund, bp. of London, 1669-1748 (Flat-box 4, Folder 10)
    The Right Reverend Father in God/Edmund Gibson Lord Bishop of London/Dean of his Majesty’s Chappels Royal and/one of his Majesty’s most Honourable privy Council./I.Ellys pinx. Geo.Vertue Sculps-t. 17... Knee piece in oblong looking left. Engraving. 37.0 x 26.9 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0532. Giffen, Johann, 17th cent. (Flat-box 4, Folder 10)
    Johannes A.Giffen./Serenissimi ac Raverendissimi Dni.Dm.Leopoldi/Guilielmi Archiducis Austriae etc. Consiliarius,/Judex Provincialis in Episcopatu Passauensi et Praefectus in Schirtnegg,/Nec non Suae Serenitatis, veluti Magni Magistri Equestris Ordini Teutonici,/ ac Episcopi Argentinensis, Halberstadiensis et Passauiensis et Lantgravij/Alsatiae etc. ad Tractatus Pads Universalis Legatus Plenipotentiarius./accessit Privilegium Caesarum./ Cum privilegio Regum et Ordinum Hollandiae./Anselmus van Hulle pinxit./Petr.de lode sculpsit. 1649. Bust looking right in oval lettered: "Qui facile credit facile decipitur”. Engraving. 30.5 x 19.8 cm. Singer No. 10800/32495. No. 11]. from: Pacificatores orbis Christiani, Rotterdain, 1697.
  - 0533. Gloxin, David, 1597-1671 (Flat-box 4, Folder 10)
    David Gloxin./Doctor: Reipubl: Lubeensis Syndicus,/eiusdemq, ut et Civitatum Hanseaticarum ad/tractatus Pads Legatus. 1649./Cun priviiegio Regum et Hollandiae Ordinum. accessit Privilegium Caesarum./Anselmus van Hulle pin. Pet. de lode sculpsit. Bust looking right in oval lettered: "Est aliquid prodire tenus, si non datur ultra”. Engraving. 30.3 x 19.5 cm. Singer No. 10960/32856. No. 117 from: Pacificatores orbis Christiani, Rotterdam, 1697.
  - 0534. Gobelius, Cornelius, ca 1648 (Flat-box 4, Folder 10)
    Cornelius Gobelius Comes Palatinus Caesareug/Reverendissimi et Celsissimi Episcopi Bambergensis Consiliarius intimus,/nec non Cathedralis Capituli et Praepositurae ibidem respective/Syndicus, et Praefectus, pro tempore nomine S.R.I: Principum/Bambergensis et Fuldensis, ad tractatus pacis Monasterium,/et Osnabrugam Legatus Plenipotentiarius./ Anselmus van Hulle pinxit. Petr.de lode sculpsit. Cum privilegio Regum et Hollandiae Ordinum accessit Privilegium Caesareum, 1649. Bust, looking right in oval lettered: "Optima consula malorum remedia”. Engraving. 30.2 x 19.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. Singer No. 10987/32947. Unnumbered leaf from: Hulle A. van, Pacificatores Orbis Christiani, Rotterdaiu, 1697.
  - 0535. Godeau, Antoine, bp. of Venice, 1605-1672 (Flat-box 4, Folder 10)
    Antoine Godeau./Evesque de Vence de l’Academie Francoise./Jac.Lubin sculp. Bust in oval looking right, framed by oblong. Engraving. 24.8 x 19.4 cm. Singer No. 10992/32958. a. -
  - 0536. Godfrey, Sir Edmund Berry, ?-1678 (Flat-box 4, Folder 10)
    Sr. Edmond Bury Godfrey/Obit 1678./Engraved by R.Dunkarton from an/Original Picture supposed by Sr. G.Kneller/London Published by S.Woodburn, 1812. Bust in oval looking right. Mezzotint. 15.8 x 10.7 cm.
  - 0537. Godolphin, Sidney, 1st earl of, 1645-1712 (Flat-box 4, Folder 10)